<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Panos Karabelas</title>
    <link>https://panoskarabelas.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Panos Karabelas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://panoskarabelas.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Screen space shadows</title>
      <link>https://panoskarabelas.com/posts/screen_space_shadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panoskarabelas.com/posts/screen_space_shadows/</guid>
      <description>After working on Spartan game engine for so long, it became increasingly obvious that there are many interesting things that I could be writing about. However, I kept postponing it as I was growing fond of Hugo and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to invest any content (or money) on WordPress anymore. The good thing is that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the courage to transition to this slick and fast site you&amp;rsquo;re browsing now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://panoskarabelas.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panoskarabelas.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Panos, I&amp;rsquo;m the author of Spartan Engine and a Senior Rendering Programmer @ Codemasters.
Click here for my CV.
This site is used both for blogging and as a portfolio.
 Motto
&amp;ldquo;If something is important enough, you do it, even if the odds are not in your favor.&amp;rdquo; Elon Musk
 Games I like
 Alan Wake Assetto Corsa Colin McRae Rally, Dirt Rally and Dirt Doom Dying Light Fallout Far Cry Forza Motorsport Grand Theft Auto Gran Turismo Hitman Just Cause Kerbal Space Program LA Noire Mass Effect Max Payne Metal Gear Solid Quantum Break Sherlock Holmes Skyrim Subnautica The Last of Us Uncharted Wolfenstein  Movies I like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://panoskarabelas.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panoskarabelas.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Present - Dirt 5  Can&amp;rsquo;t share anything at the moment.
Team: Codemasters • Platform: PC, Stadia, PS4, PS4, Xbox One, Xbox Series X • Tools: C++, Custom • Location: UK
 2017 to 2020 - VR game (cancelled)  I left Greece and moved to the UK to work on an ambitious VR title which after a few years, was cancelled. I worked on some cool things which I am (unfortunately) not allowed to share.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>