<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Panos Karabelas</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Panos Karabelas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Panos, I&amp;rsquo;m the author of Spartan Engine and an MTS Software Development Engineer @ AMD.&#xA;Click here for my CV.&#xA;This site is used both for blogging and as a portfolio.&#xA;Motto&#xA;&amp;ldquo;If something is important enough, you do it, even if the odds are not in your favor.&amp;rdquo; Elon Musk&#xA;Games I like&#xA;Alan Wake Colin McRae Rally, Dirt Rally and Dirt Doom Dying Light Fallout Far Cry Grand Theft Auto Gran Turismo Hitman Kerbal Space Program LA Noire Mass Effect Max Payne Metal Gear Solid Quantum Break Resident Evil Skyrim Subnautica Uncharted Wolfenstein Movies I like</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>2022 to 2023 - Multiple titles Worked with studios across the UK, helping them achieve high performance on AMD GPUs.&#xA;Team: AMD • Platform: PC • Tools: Lot&amp;rsquo;s of them • Location: UK&#xA;2020 - Dirt 5 Worked as a senior graphics programmer.&#xA;Team: Codemasters • Platform: PC, Stadia, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X • Tools: C++, Neon Engine • Location: UK&#xA;2017 to 2020 - VR game (cancelled) I left Greece and moved to the UK to work on an ambitious VR title which after a few years, was cancelled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screen space shadows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/screen_space_shadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/screen_space_shadows/</guid>
      <description>After working on Spartan game engine for so long, it became increasingly obvious that there are many interesting things that I could be writing about. However, I kept postponing it as I was growing fond of Hugo and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to invest any content (or money) on WordPress anymore. The good thing is that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the courage to transition to this slick and fast site you&amp;rsquo;re browsing now!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
